闇よりも
More Than
The Darkness
闇よりも
More Than
The Darkness
奇形…
Mutants…
村に１人の少年が住んでいた
There lived a boy in the village.
とても そうめいな子だったが
He was a boy of great intelligence, but he had one weakness.
１つの欠点があった
瞬！ あっ…
Shun!
Solitude was his only friend and confidant.
孤独だけが 彼の友達となり
話し相手に…
少年は知らず知らずのうちに
業を積み重ね
Unbeknownst to him, the boy’s
karma spiraled further out of control.
He had turned into a karma demon.
業魔へと変わっていった
業魔は
この世に存在してはいけない
Karma demons ought not to walk this world.
業魔は ひっそりと湖に姿を消した
He quietly walked his body to the bottom of a lake.
どこにいるの？
Where are you?
早季…
Saki.
What are you doing here?
こんな所で何してるんだ
分からない
I don’t know.
今… 私 どこにいるの？
Where… am I?
瞬… 瞬…
Shun… Shun…
Shun!
瞬！
You shouldn’t be here!
こんな所に来ちゃダメだ！
帰れ…
Go home.
イヤよ！ うっ…
No!
何が起きてるの？
教えてくれなきゃ 私
What’s going on?
I won’t budge until you tell me!
ここを動かないからね
早季…
Saki…
私は 瞬を…
I… Shun…
瞬に… 瞬…
Shun… Shun…
私 殺されそうになったんだから
I was almost killed…
猫に会ったのか
You met a cat?
Yes.
Your charm saved me.
でも 瞬にもらった
おまじないのおかげで助かったの
でも たぶん もう１匹いる
But I think there’s another cat.
10分だけだ
Ten minutes.
You can stay here for ten minutes.
10分間だけ ここにいていい
その間に できるだけの説明はする
I’ll explain as much as I can in that time.
これ 瞬がやってるの？
Is this your doing?
お面…
A mask…
Shun?
瞬…
入ろう
Come in.
Ten minutes.
10分間…
I think I can keep it under control for that long.
それくらいなら抑えられる
しかたないんだ
Sorry about that.
ちょっとの間だけ 我慢して
Please bear with them for now.
そのお面 取ってよ 何だか…
Take off that mask.
It’s so—
ダメだ
I can’t.
時間がない
We have no time.
何から話したらいいのかな
Where should I start?
瞬 一体 何が…
What’s going on, Shun?
全ての問題は
人間の心から来るんだよ
All problems stem from the human heart.
人間の心のうち
Our conscious self is just the tip of the iceberg.
意識というのは
氷山の一角にすぎない
The subconscious below the water is greater beyond comparison.
水面下にある無意識の方が
はるかに広大なんだ
That’s not what I want to know!
違うの！ そんな話じゃなくて
瞬に何が起きたのか教えてよ！
Tell me what’s happening to you!
That’s what I am talking about.
それを今 説明してるんだよ
人間は どうやっても
Despite our best efforts, we humans cannot fully control our thoughts and feelings.
自分の心を
完全に制御することはできない
Our subconscious, in particular, is rife with the unpredictable.
特に無意識の中では
思ってもみないことが起きている
それは呪力において
最も顕著にあらわれるんだ
Our Cantus is the most tangible manifestation of this.
In the case of physical actions, there are multiple stages between the inception deep down and the eventual effect.
物理的な行動を起こす場合
心に思い描いたことが
実際に起きるまでは
いくつかの段階がある
Although the original impetus is a product of our subconscious,
動機は無意識から発していても
行動に移す前には
it needs to pass through our conscious thought before it can be realized.
意識の領域を
通過しなければならないから
Human reason can correct or altogether stop an action from being taken.
理性によって
ストップをかけられたり
修正したりすることができる
Cantus works differently, however.
だけど 呪力の場合
We can consider the inception and execution of an action to be practically simultaneous.
思ったことが実現するまで
ほとんど同時といってもいい
仮に間違っていたとしても
修正する暇がないんだ
Though it may be the wrong action, there is no time to correct it.
間違う… どういうこと？
Wrong? What do you mean?
イメージをちゃんと作らないと
呪力は発動しないでしょう？
Isn’t using our Cantus tied to picturing very specific things?
Some mental images are clearly and consciously conceived,
そのイメージにも
明確に意識されているものと
while others are shrouded in the darkness of the subconscious.
無意識の闇に
飲み込まれたままのものがある
だけど 皆 分かっていない
Nobody realizes this.
呪力は 暗示や真言を使って
We try to keep our Canti strictly
controlled through hypnosis and mantras.
厳格に管理しようとしてる
でもね 無意識下に開いた出口から
But in the end, it always leaks through
the holes opened by our subconscious.
必ず漏出が起きるんだ
漏出…
Leaks through?
呪力は常に漏れ出している
Our Canti are constantly leaking out.
僕らは ある意味では
無意識の命ずるままに
In a sense, we are changing the world around us at the whim of our subconsciousness.
周囲の世界に
変化をもたらし続けているんだ
そんな…
But…
早季は
八丁標が何のためにあると思う？
What do you think the Holy Barrier is for?
それは…
Well…
Do you think it’s there to protect us from unknown threats outside of it?
外からくる
得体の知れないモノから
僕たちを守るため？
そうでしょう
Isn’t it?
No.
違う 八丁標は外敵ではなく
The Holy Barrier defends against
internal threats, not external ones.
内なる敵に対処するために
作られたんだ
Internal threats?
内なる… 敵
絶えず漏出してる 僕たちの呪力だ
It’s our own, constantly leaking Cantus.
悪鬼にせよ 業魔にせよ
Consider fiends or karma demons.
結局 僕らにとって恐怖とは
内からやってくるものなんだ
We ultimately fear what spawns from within us.
もちろん 漏出している呪力は
ごく微弱だから
Of course, the Canti that leaks out is feeble and won’t ravage the world overnight.
一朝一夕に
どうかなるものじゃない
But if our thoughts and ideas continue to amass and interfere with each other for an extended period of time,
でも長期間お互いの思念に
干渉 蓄積し続ければ
その影響は計り知れない
then there is no predicting the results.
だから どうしても
それを外に向けてやる必要がある
This means there is a need to direct it outwards.
僕らは幼い頃から繰り返し
Since our childhood, we’ve been
conditioned to fear the outside world.
外の世界に対する恐怖を
刷り込まれてきた
だけど
巨大な暗黒世界のイメージは
However, an image of that dark,
boundless world also exists within us.
僕らの内にもある
もう１つの暗黒の宇宙である
It becomes one with the dark universe inside ourselves—our subconscious.
無意識と
同一化されるようになる
心の中で 無意識を
外の世界と直結させることで
By linking our subconscious to the outside world,
漏出を八丁標の外へと導くんだ
we direct such leakages outside the Holy Barrier.
八丁標は 僕らの｢みそぎ｣のための
The Holy Barrier is like a charm required for our purification.
おまじないみたいなものだ
じゃあ その外へ出された呪力は
どうなるの？
What does the Cantus do outside the barrier?
ミノシロの祖先は
The minoshiro’s ancestor is most likely a sea slug.
おそらく
海にいる ミノウミウシだろうけど
Are you saying the leakage of our Canti created the minoshiro?
私たちから漏出した呪力が
ミノシロを作ったってこと？
ミノシロだけじゃない
トラバサミも
Not only the minoshiro.
Tigercrabs and haythatchers as well.
カヤノスヅクリだってそうだ
それが正しいかどうか
私には分からない
I don’t know if you’re correct or not.
でも…
But…
でも 正直 言ってどうでもいい
But I really don’t think it matters either!
私が知りたいのは…
I just want to know…
私が… 知りたいのは
I just want to know what’s happening to you!
瞬の身に
何が起きたかってことだけなの
大丈夫 すばるだよ
Don’t worry.
That’s Subaru.
おいで
Come here.
何も… 僕は 本当に…
None of this… I really…
何もしたくなかったんだ
I didn’t want to do any of this.
分かるだろう？
Do you understand now?
All this is the result of what’s happening to me.
これが
僕に起きたことの結果なんだよ
呪力の漏出が止まらないんだ
My Cantus just won’t stop escaping.
It’s also growing in intensity, and
I’m less and less able to control it.
それも どんどん激しく
制御不能になりつつある
無意識の暴走により
呪力の異常漏出が起きて
My subconsciousness has gone out of control, resulting in extreme leakages of my Cantus.
周囲のもの 全てが
破壊的な影響を受け
Under its destructive effects,
everything around me is warped.
異形化してしまう
これが
橋本･アッペルバウム症候群だ
This is the Hashimoto-Appelbaum syndrome.
I’ve…
僕は…
業魔になった
…turned into a karma demon.
そんな ウソよ…
That can’t be…
残念ながら 本当だ
It’s sad but true.
ここにある本は
All these books contain knowledge that was
supposed to have been consigned to oblivion.
永遠に葬り去るべき知識と
されているものばかりだ
早季のお母さんが
特別に貸してくれた
Your mother went out of her way to lend them to me.
お母さんが…？
My mother?
業魔化という現象について
知識を得るには
Reading these books is the only way to learn
what changing into a karma demon is all about.
これを読む以外にない
これが 分かっている全てなんだ
This is all we know.
僕は自分自身の記録を付けている
I’m writing down my own experience too.
やがては
いちばん新しい症例として…
In the end, I’m merely the most recent case.
僕の名前も ここに加わることに
I have to add my name to the list.
そんなこと言わないでよ
Don’t say that.
それより どうすれば瞬は治るの？
Is there any way we can reverse this?
呪力を封印することは
できないの？
Can’t we seal your Cantus?
無瞋上人に
施術をしてもらったんだ
Head Priest Mushin tried that already.
僕の呪力は
蓋が壊れたような状態で…
My Cantus is like something with a broken lid.
止めることは
It’s unlikely that anything can hold it back now.
できないらしい
それって もしかして…
Is it because…
私が間違ったやり方で
瞬の呪力を復活させたから
…I didn’t restore your Cantus correctly?
早季のせいじゃない！
It’s not your fault!
そろそろ帰った方がいい
You should go home now.
僕は今 ありったけの呪力を
ハチ玉に向けることで
I’m focusing all my Cantus on the wasp balls right now so that it doesn’t affect you.
君に影響が及ぶのを防いでいる
集中力が鈍ると
Once my concentration wanes, I can’t say when it will become uncontrollable again.
いつ暴走が始まるか分からない
イヤ！ 帰らない 一緒にいたい
No! I won’t go!
I want to be with you!
Saki.
早季… 僕は このために
My condition has already caused the death of my parents.
両親を死なせてしまった
So please go home!
だから帰ってくれ！
これ以上 僕のために
I don’t want anyone else I love to die in front of me!
愛する人が死ぬのは
見たくないんだ！
I…
私には…
瞬は救えない
…can’t save you.
私には 何もできない！
I can’t do anything!
Shun.
瞬…
Is there anything you want me to do?
私に 何かしてほしいことは？
早季 やめろ！
Saki, no!
やめて…
Stop…
瞬…
Shun!
Subaru tried to rescue me.
すばるは 僕を助けようとしたんだ
そんなことをしても
何にもならないのに
Despite how futile it was…
何度も置いて行こうとしたんだ
I tried to leave him behind many, many times.
でも どうしても付いてくる
Still, he followed me every time.
本当は 僕の方が
寂しかったのかもしれない
Perhaps I was the lonely one.
すばるがいなくなったら
I’d be all alone without Subaru.
ひとりぼっちになっちゃうから…
あの猫だって
別に悪くなかったんだ
It’s not the cat’s fault either.
ただ 命令どおり 僕を
It’s here simply because it was ordered to end my life.
僕の始末をつけに来た
So you see…
だから…
僕がやるべきことを決断する
タイミングが遅かった
I’ve taken too long to decide on what I should’ve done.
でも…
But…
もっと早く
決着をつけるべきだった
I should have ended this much sooner.
僕がずるずると引き伸ばしたから
If I hadn’t been so indecisive,
すばるを…
Subaru wouldn’t have had to suffer like this.
こんな目にあわせちゃった…
たくさんの錠剤が入った瓶を
I was given a bottle of pills before I came here.
ここへ来る直前にもらったんだ
A combination of various types of poison.
いろんな種類の
毒の詰合せなんだよ
Don’t you think it’s a cruel parting gift?
ひどい せん別だと思わないか
I’m glad you didn’t take any of them.
そんなの 飲まなくてよかったわ
You should’ve just thrown them all away.
捨てちゃえばいいのに
I took them all.
They just didn’t work.
飲んだよ
だけど 効かなかったんだ
分子性の毒は
簡単に変性してしまうらしいね
I guess it’s easy to detoxify poisons on a molecular level.
死にたくないという無意識が
My subconscious desire to survive
must’ve altered the elements themselves.
元素まで
変換してしまったのかもしれない
I think it’s coming.
来るみたいだ
What do you mean?
何が…？
早く ここを出るんだ
Leave now.
僕の家が
大地に飲み込まれた時と同じだ
The same happened when my
home was swallowed by the earth.
笑っちゃうだろう
Isn’t it funny?
祝霊にそっくりだから
It’s just like the Spirit of Blessing.
こっちは
祝福を与えてくれるどころか
Yet instead of blessing you, all it brings is death.
死の使いだけどね
早く！
Hurry!
今度こそ 終わりにするよ
I’ll put an end to it now.
もうたくさんだ
I’ve had enough!
早季…
Saki…
ずっと好きだった
I’ve always loved you.
さようなら…
Goodbye.
瞬～！
Shun!
私は… 生きなければならない
I have to stay alive.
Episode Ten
More Than
The Darkness
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
僕のことは
もう忘れてしまったの？
Have you forgotten about me already?